Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- [?], Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 19 August 1810., 1 page. L. (Folder 623)
  The two young men who contracted with Shepherd for flour have been at all mills and cannot get flour. Will have to give you the price you ask.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Lexington, [Virginia], to William Walker. Craig's Creek, Botetourt [County, Virginia], 13 September 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 624)
  Salutation is "Dear And[re]w." Wishes him to write respecting the receipts for costs in the suit with the Wilson's and Harbison's bond. "As I of late feel my constitution decline, my wish is as far as possible to draw my concerns to a close. Ask [George] Hancock to have business in Botetourt with Wilson's settled." "have not got my business with Lewis finally settled as yet..."
- W[illia]m Walker, Botetourt [County, Virginia], to uncle Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia. 25 September 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 625)
  Presented receipts to [?] Wilson. He would not refund the money. Left receipts and letter with [George] Hancock."I start in a few days for Kentucky with my little family & small portion of this world's goods--my wife [Elenor] has been in a bad state of health since early spring. My mother & brother And[re]w also are in bad health as usual. Write if you receive this letter. Address letter to Lincoln County near Stanford Kentucky."
- Jonathan Purdy, 2 Batt[alion], O[hio] C[ounty] M[ilitia], Grave Creek [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Col, 1st Bat[talio]n, O[hio] C[ounty] M[ilitia], n.p., 1 October 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 626)
  Lists officers elected by company.
- W[illia]m McGuire, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p. Offers to sell stills, 2 October 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 627)
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to W[illia]m Lewis, Botetourt [County, Virginia], 5 October 1810., 1 page. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 628)
  Wants to meet him in Staunton.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Thomas Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 8 October 1810., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 629)
  Lists terms on which he will settle with Lewis.
- James Laidley, Wood Court House, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 18 October 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 630)
  Introduces [?] McKnight who claims land in Ohio County.
- A. Caldwell, Wheeling Mills, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., [November 1810]., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 631)
  Terms upon which he will sell his farm, mill, dwelling house and distillery.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Skinner & Barber, n.p., 14 December 1810., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 632)
  Terms on which Josiah Dillon will pay Bank of Marietta.
- David Putnam, Bank of Marietta, [Ranesville, Ohio] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 December 1810., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 633)
  Terms upon which the directors will accept payment of Dillon's debt.
- Memorandum of agreement between Josiah Dillon and Archibald Woods, 29 December 1810., 1 page. Copy of DS. (Folder 634)
  Woods will take up Dillon's note on Bank of Marietta. Dillon will convey house and lot to Woods. Dillon will convey residue of property to Geo[rge] Paull.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 December 1810., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 635)
  Has offered for Congress. Chancellor made decree in [Woods vs. Lewis]. Decree is agreeable to last verdict.
- [Archibald Woods] to [?], [1811?]., 1 page. ACy of AL. (Folder 636)
  Questioning whether a judgment against Josiah Dillon in federal court is a lien against property he has bought from Woods.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Will[ia]m Poage, Staunton, [Virginia], [1811]., 3 pages. Copy of ALS. (Folder 637)
  Asks Poage to collect money due in execution of decree in [ Woods vs. Lewis]. Gives Poage directions about collecting it.
- Thomas Boyles, n.p., to [Archibald] Woods,[1811]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 638)
  Intends to get money to Woods.
- [Archibald Woods] to Elijah McClandhan, Sheriff of Botetourt [County, Virginia], [1811]., 1 page. (Folder 639)
  Wants McClandhan to collect money due on execution against W[illia]m Lewis.
  Includes, ACy of AL, [Archibald Woods] to Ja[me]s Breckinridge. Woods blames Breckenridge for not paying over money owed him by William Lewis. 1 page.
- Agreement between Thomas Nichols and Archi[bal]d Woods for Woods to deliver flour, 13 January 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 640)
- Robert Pogue, Mason County, Kentucky, to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 13 January 1811., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 641)
  [?] Hughes received fee who will handle Woods' business with Bell. Pogue obtained judgment for 7,000 dollars against [?] Brown. Gives family news.
- Promissary note of [Archibald Woods] to Moses Shepherd for three hundred dollars, 18 January 1811., 1 page. D. (Folder 642)
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Rob[er]t Poage, near Mays Lick, Kentucky, 18 January 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 643)
  Wants to know if [?] Hughes brought suit against [Benjamin] Bell for him. It not, will employ Alex[ande]r Marshall next.
- James Dunlap, Canonsburgh, [sic] [Pennsylvania], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 January 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 644)
  Describes college at Canonsburgh.
- James Smith, n.p., to Andrew Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 January 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 645)
  Wants all papers pertaining to lease of a piece of property sent to him.
- Zebulon Warner, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 February 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 646)
  Has purchased property of John Thompson. Woods is at liberty to make use of his house after expiration of the lease.
- John Lee, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 February 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 646A)
  Requests pay for services as adjutant in 4th Regiment of Virginia militia.
- William Downey, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Virgniey [Virginia], 11 February 1811., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 647)
  Recounts his difficulty in obtaining money.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 12 February 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 648)
  Has had no further account from Staunton. "I had expected to see Genll Paull present my compl[iments] to [?] and tell him to be so good as to procure a copy of your Constitution on Regulations of your Library and forward to me as soon as possible as I am to report on that subject for our town is establishing a library."
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 14 February 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 649)
  Encloses a decree against [William] Lewis. Clerk has failed to certify when the injunction was granted.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 March 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 650)
  Cannot be at election [in Ohio County, Virginia]. Hopes his opponent will not exceed him in that County more than 30 votes.
- Alexander Reed, Washington, [Pennsylvania], to John McLure, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 15 March 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 651)
  Wants [?] Woods [son of Archibald Woods] to come next week if he is coming to live with him. Will leave terms up to McLure.
- Geor[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods,15 March 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 652)
  Brown wants to rent house. Wants a sign and four beds and complains of rent being too high.
- Deed (witnessed by Edw[ard] Bryson and Sam[ue]1 Dillon) between George Paull of the first part, Josiah Dillon and Dorothy Dillon of the second part and Archibald Woods of the third part, 29 March 1811., 4 pages. DS. (Folder 653)
  George Paull had held deed of trust on two lots in St. Clairsville, Ohio for money owed Bank of Marietta by Dillon. Paull is deeding property to Woods to discharge the deed of trust. Edw[ard] Bryson. 1 page. Includes affidavit of William Farris, Jun[io]r. 1 page.
- Archi[bald] Woods, n.p., to John White, n.p., 3 April 1811. (Folder 654)
  Horse bought by White or his brother in St. Clairsville, [Ohio] stands on lot bought by Woods from Josiah Dillon.
- Polly Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Ann Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 April 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 655)
- Samuel Moore, Archa [Archibald] Wood[s], Wheelan [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 8 October 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 656)
  Shall be engaged at Judge Lockwood fitting out a boat. Mortgage must be recorded.
- Lease from Archi[bal]d Woods to Josiah McGuire, 15 April 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 657)
- W[illia]m Chapline, Jr., Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling Creek, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 16 April 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 658)
  Asks Woods to survey land to divide farm between Chapline and Evans.
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] and Martin Gaunt of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] for Gaunt to lease land from Woods, 19 April 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 659)
- Geo[rge] Hancock, Fincastle, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling near Pittsburg[h], Virginia [West Virginia], 25 April 1811., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 660)
  Lewis has deposited money with General [James] Breckinridge for Woods' claim. [?] Walker previous to going to Kentucky left memo respecting Woods' suit with Wilson. No bill was filed.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Washington, [D.C.] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 April 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 660A)
  Results of election between W[illia]m McKinley and Wilson.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to D[aniel] Sheffey, n.p., 2 May 1811., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 661)
  Has not heard from lawyers concerning Woods vs. Lewis. Th[oma]s Wilson is elected to Congress.
- Agreement between Josiah McGuire and Michel Brown, carpenters and Archi[bal]d Woods, for work to be done Woods' house, 7 May 1811., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 662)
  Lists tasks and prices.
- Geo[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Virginia [West Virginia], 9 May 1811., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 663)
  Concerns the discharge of the deed of trust by Paull and the validity of Woods' title to Dillon's property.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Isaac Hutchinson, Clerk of Monroe County, at union, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 664)
  Asks if copy of decree in [ Woods vs. Lewis] has been forwarded.
- Archi[bal]d Wood[s], n.p., to George Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], 28 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 665)
  [Noah?] Linsly has decided against Woods and Paull concerning the discharge of the deed of trust by Paull selling Dillon's lots to Woods.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Wil[lia]m R. Dickinson, Cash[ie]r Bank at Steubenville, [Ohio], 21 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 666)
  Transmits payment to discharge note.
- Geo[rge] Evans, agent of Oliver Evans, Pittsburgh Steam Mill to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 667)
  Concerning the price of a hopperboy for a flour mill.
- D[aniel] Sheffey, Montgomery County, Virginia, to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia, 25 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 668)
  Apologizes for delay. Called away by death of a friend in Baltimore. Has sent copy of decree to clerk of Monroe so he can issue execution.
- Geo[rge] Paull, n.p., to James Paull, Pennsylvania, 28 May 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 669)
  Wants James Paull to send him a pair of pigs.
- C. Johnson, Staunton, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 June 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 670)
  Sends decree in Woods vs. Lewis.
- Execution issued by Jno Ewing and Sam[ue]l McClure8 June 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 671)
  Issued against property of Amos Shearman and Joseph Ferroi in the lawsuit of Matthew Kerr vs. Ferroi.
- Benj[ami]n Biggs, B[rigadier] Gen[era]l, West Liberty,[Virginia] [West Virginia] to Lt. Col. Arch[ibal]d Wood[s], n.p., 8 June-20 June 1811., 2 items. 1 page. (Folder 672)
  Appoints Woods president of a court-martial to try James G. Laidley for disorderly behaviour and disobedience of orders at the 113th Regiment. "Also for conspiring with his subaltern officers previous to s[ai]d muster to be disorderly on the day of said muster."
  Includes, DS, of Benj[ami]n Biggs, certifying he did employ John Finney to summons the officers to attend the trial of L[a]idley. 2 items.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to David Erwin, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 June 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 673)
  Requests Erwin pay forty-two dollars to [?] Evans for license to rise hopperboy at Woods' mill. "The mill stands on Wheat's run a branch of Wheeling Creeke, [sic] in Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia]..."
- Geo[rge] Hancock, Fincastle, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling near Pittsburg[h, Virginia],12 June 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 674)
  Sends bill [of complaint] for Woods to answer in Wilson's Ex[ecut]ors vs. Woods.
- Jno. W. Pleasants, Council Chamber, City of Richmond, [Virginia] to the Commandant of the 4th Regiment [Virginia Militia] Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 June 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 675)
  Instructed by Lieutenant Governor "to inform you that commissions cannot issue...until it shall be specified...what vacancies they are to fill; or if for a new company that also should be specified."
- Appointment, of Andrew Howlett as a captain in the fourth Regiment tenth Brigade and third Division of the Virginia militia, 25 June 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 676)
  Signed by Geo[rge] W[illia]m Smith, Lieutenant Governor and J[no] W. Pleasants.
  Includes, DS, of Benj[amin] Biggs attesting that Andrew Howlett had taken oath as captain. 1 page.
- Zac. Sprigg, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 29 June 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 677)
  Needs oats from Woods.
- M[atthe]w Houston, Natural Bridge, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 6 July 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 678)
  Joseph Cloyd's wife and daughter died. Houston's "son Andrew got a cut on his knee last winter which had nearly taken his life." Gives other family news.
- [Archibald Woods], Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Geory[e] Hancock, n.p., 8 July 1811., 2 items. (Folder 679)
  Concerning Woods vs. Lewis and Wilson's heirs vs. Woods.
- Bonds (witnessed by Noah Linsly) of Archibald Woods with Moses Shepherd, William Irwin, Noah Zane and Noah Linsly, 18 July 1811., 1 page. D. (Folder 680)
- S. McClure, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 19 July 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 681)
  Has made an alteration in the [promissory] note Woods sent for him to sign.
  Includes ALS, of John Anderson, n.d., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia. Robert Anderson is not willing that John Anderson should quit his work before harvest so Woods can expect them July 15. 1 page.
- Benj[ami]n Biggs, Br[igadier] Gen[eral], 10th Brigade, to Col. Arch[ibald] Wood[s], n.p., 6 August 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 682)
  Orders Woods to order regiment to Wheeling for muster.
- D[aniel] Sheffey, Montgomery Court House, [Virginia], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 9 August 1811., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 683)
  Has collected 792 dollars in execution granted in Woods vs. Lewis. Marshall has taken all the personal property of William Lewis. Let him know how to transmit money.
- Agreement (witnessed by Spencer Biddle and Damiel [?]) between Lloyd Biddle of Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia] and Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 August 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 684)
  For Woods to lease the stone house and stable to be built. Describes how stable is to be constructed.
- John McLure, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibald] Woods, n.p., 5 September 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 685)
  Sent articles written for.
- And[re]w Woods, n.p., to Brother Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 5 September 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 686)
  Sends sympathy for death of Archibald Woods' son. Unable to attend funeral.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 6 September 1811., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 687)
  Pleased with executive appointment of a judge for our circuit. Try to block appointment of [?] Jackson by legislature. Thinks [Congressional] session will be long and boisterous. His reception in Woods' County has made impressions on his mind.
- Agreement between Thomas Evans of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] and Zebudiah Meix of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 14 September 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 688)
  Meix agrees to build a barn for Evans. Description of how it is to be built.
- Jesse Hunt, Newels town, [Newell, Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheelen, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia] 15 September 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 689)
  Offers land for sale adjoining land owned by Woods at the mouth of Capteen Creek.
- John Wilson, Washington, Pennsylvania, to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 October 1811., 1 page. PD. (Folder 690)
  Notifies Woods that a note of Michael Cresap, endorsed by Woods is due and unpaid.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to [?] Griffith, St. Clairsville, [Ohio]. 5 October 1811., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 691)
  Zebu Warner is indebted to Woods for rent. Gives Griffith options on how to handle the collection.
  Includes ALS, of Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Zebu Warner, n.p. concerns rent owed to Woods. 1 page.
- 8 October 1811. (Folder See 656)
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 October 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 692)
  Laments loss of Woods' son. Not able to make any statement with respect to Woods' account with Geo[rge] Poage without assistance of Woods' papers.
  Includes receipt from J. Russle [?] to David Banes[?] for wheat to the account of A[rchibald] Woods. 1 page.
  Includes, fragment of an account. 1 page.
- John Beach, Marietta, [Ohio], to Archable [Archibald] Wood[s], Wheelling [Wheeling], [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 October 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 693)
  If Woods has made purchase of the Jughandle Mills, write him and he will send Woods a draft of his proportion of the halfe [sic].
- Geo[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods near Wheeling, Virginia [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 October 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 694)
  Spoke to R. [?] Thompson who is considered one of the best house-carpenters here respecting the undertaking of your house. The Republican ticket succeeded in all three members with a majority of two to three hundred votes.
- Arch[ibald] Woods, n.p., to Elig[a]h McClandhan, Botetourt [County, Virginia], 26 October 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 695)
  Has learned by George Paull that Mr. Lewis has sold his land. Informed a proposition is made by Mr. Lewis to pay to W[illia]m Poage of Augusta [for Woods]. Thanks McClandhan for his friendly aid in having the business brought to a close. Speculates on other terms.
- Jo[seph] Cloyd, Natural Bridge, [Virginia] to Uncle Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 12 November 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 696)
  Concerns taxes on land in Ohio County owned by Cloyd family and by M[atthe]w Houston.
- John Gosney, n.p., to Archabal [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia, [sic] [West Virginia], 13 November 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 697)
  Wants Woods to make him some flour.
- Isaac Kelly, n.p., to the Register of the Land Office at Richmond, Virginia, 15 November 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 698)
  Asks that he look for patents for George and Isaac Kelly.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Washington, [D.C.] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 November 1811., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 699)
  Asks Woods to tell him how to go about military patents. Has visited the President and also attended the House of Madam. At next interview with President intends to mention the Road. Many petitioners praying to be relieved from injuries sustained under the nonimportation law. Affair of the Chesapeake settled. Determined representation for the states. The "Harriet" sails in a few days with messengers to England and France. Mr. Taylor son of Jno Taylor goes to England and Mr. Biddle son of Clement Biddle goes to France. "it is hard to say what course our great men will take. I believe...leaders know not what to do. Not do I know who is to be the leader. I believe in Caucus it was determined to elect H[enry] Clay, speaker and they did elect him." Describes Clay.
- S. R. Bakewell, Charlestown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods near Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 26 November 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 700)
  Has about thirty-five feet of pipes now by him and expects to set another kiln next week when he expects to have Woods' in it. Wants to know what other kind, of ware Woods would wish to be sent along with them. "Here let me remark that Mr. Wales opinion of stone ware pipes is higher than ever & he regrets that the town of Steubensville does not use them instead of wood."
- Power of attorney (witnessed by Noah Zane and Noah Linsly) from Moses Shepherd to Noah Linsly, 29 November 1811., 1 page. DS. (Folder 701)
  To assign and transfer to Archibald Woods twenty shares in Bank of Steubenville.
- Tho[ma]s Woods, Washington, [Pennsylvania], to father [Archibald Woods], 9 December 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 702)
  Gives his recollection of a transaction between himself and John McClure. Mr. Reed's young daughter died. Have searched for cloth.
- Andrew Howlett, n.p., to Archeble [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 18 December 1811., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 703)
  Apologizes for being so long, in making his returns because he couldn't understand it.
  Includes, ALS, from Andrew Howlett to Archebel [Archibald] Woods, 30 December 1811. Has sent returns by Moses Chaplin[e]. 1 page. ALS.
- Memorandum of business for Tho[mas] Woods to attend to for Archibald Woods, [1812?]., 1 page. M. (Folder 704)
  Concerns settling Woods vs. Lewis. "Beware of being taken in as all those people are Great Sharpers. Beware of going in any barter or bargain with them. If possible they will try to pawn some old or good for nothing Negroes on you, or some other old stuff or bad bonds."
- W[illia]m Poage, Augusta [County, Virginia] to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 January 1812., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 705)
  Received four hundred dollars from [William] Lewis. Taken a bond on Burwell. Not knowing the amount of the Ex[ecution] nor Cred[i]ts, could not go into a final settlement. Can have it credited to execution by writing clerk of Monroe or attorney.
- P[olly] Wilson, Morgantown [Virginia] [West Virginia], to sister Anna [Ann] Wood[s], Whe[e]ling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 January 1812., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 706)